{"id":"2018_12","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"All the ends of the earth will remember and turn to the Lord, and all the families of the nations will bow down before him.\" â€“ Psalm 22:27","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_12_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_2","questionText":"2. From the past week's study, what made the most significant impact to you in the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 18.\nDavid experienced strained relations with Saul and strong relationships with Saul's children.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"18:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_12_3","questionText":"3. What is most interesting to you concerning David's relationships with Saul, Jonathan and Michal. Why?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_4","questionText":"4. What lessons or warnings do you learn from Saul? In what area of your life could you apply these lessons?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_5","questionText":"5. How does David experience both the blessing and cost of following God? How have you seen both the blessing and cost of following Jesus in your own life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 19 with Psalm 59.\nSaul's children protected David from their father.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"19:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"59:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_12_6","questionText":"6. What risks did Jonathan and Michal take to protect David?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_7","questionText":"7. Where is God calling you to do what is right even at personal cost or risk to yourself?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_8","questionText":"8. How does Psalm 59 deepen your insight into David's faith and the danger he faced? How did David's faith strengthen him?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"59:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_12_9","questionText":"9. How might describing and naming God in your prayers transform your present outlook?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 20.\nDavid and Jonathan prepared a plan to protect David from Saul.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"20:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_12_10","questionText":"10. What do you learn about Jonathan through his words and actions? What do you find most commendable? (1 Samuel 18-20)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"18:1-20:999"}]},{"id":"2018_12_11","questionText":"11. Why would Jonathan give loyalty to David instead of Saul? What does Jonathan seem to understand about David? (Use any Scripture reference.)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_12_12","questionText":"12. What does David's and Jonathan's relationship teach you about true friendship?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Psalms 23 and 36.\nDavid praised God for His protection and love.","questions":[{"id":"2018_12_13","questionText":"13. How does David describe God's tender care in Psalm 23? Which aspect of God's care is most meaningful to you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"23:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_12_14","questionText":"14. How does David's understanding of the sinfulness of the wicked compare to your view of sin? (Psalm 36)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"36:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_12_15","questionText":"15. How does David's understanding of God help you today?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 18-20 with Psalms 23, 36, and 59.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"18:1-20:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_12_16","questionText":"16. What have you learned in this week's study about God or about the suffering of every believer?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}